And I call the order the regular meeting for the City Council for August 2nd, 2021.
Public input on schedule personal appearances.
None.
Three consent agenda staff recommends we approve out of the four through seven.
So.
Second.
Davis.
All right.
He's down.
I'm sorry.
Don't go.
Hi.
He's down.
Mayor's nomination to a point Shannon do honk and complete the.
Term of Stacey Satterwhite vacated position on the Miami.
Community and facilities authority MCFA board term expires 630 of 2022.
So move.
Second.
Hi.
He's down.
Davis.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
9.
Approved six months master.
We're in Olson.
This is what we talked about in MN2A.
I'd like to motion to approve.
Second.
Parker.
Five.
Seven.
Ten.
Approval of amendment to antenna.
Collocation.
Police.
Agreement.
Collocation.
Lisa.
Grant.
Spectrum.
Realty.
County LLC.
This is an amendment to a contract that was originally entered in 2000.
In the combined.
It was a five year term.
Initially with five.
Five year options to prevent to renew.
So we're.
By my calculations, we're in the third of those.
We know three little terms at this point.
Basically, they're wanting to change out some of the equipment on the tower.
That is required.
The modification of the contract.
That's what we're asking.
We would like to take this opportunity to point out.
This is another example of where the city and MN2A have been perhaps sloppy.
And distinguishing between the two entities.
And this particular instance.
The contract is between.
The MN and the city.
But all the money goes to MN2A.
Because that's the way they nested up in 2005.
So again, I just want to take this as an opportunity.
Say we need the more careful.
And how were your designating.
Which entity is doing what?
But the bottom line is that they're changing out equipment.
We need to approve this.
I agree with that.
Pull out that habit.
What's the fix?
If it's wrong, how do we fix it?
It's been wrong since the ghetto.
And I think that that error carries through the remainder of the term.
But this is just one of many examples where it's.
It's just been confusion on everybody's part, including the city's part,
just need to be more cautious, and how we're doing it in the future.
I'll make a motion wait for you.
Second.
Davis.
Hi.
Don't go.
He's down.
All right.
December.
Hi.
I'm Steve.
11.
Approve outside organizational contracts.
For fiscal year 21.
22.
With community crisis center.
Grand Gateway.
Peleban.
And my youngest senior.
Center.
It's June.
Yeah.
So this is the annual contract that we have with, but we kind of turn them outside organizations.
And the reason why we term them.
Call them that is because they all use the same essential contract with just a very few changes.
Got the same template.
I put in the VA.
What each entity gets, community crisis center gets a $10,000 utility credit.
The mine, the senior center gets a $12,000 utility credit.
$12,000 in reimburse expenses.
And they also get $12,000 for docs services.
They used to pay them $1,000 rent.
And they lost some, excuse me, some federal funding.
So the city took over that portion of that expense also.
That's $3600 package.
And then Peleban.
It's $46,000 of reimburse expenses.
These are the same numbers that we've had for several years.
That's a total of $70,000 in cash and $22,000 in utility credit.
The changes presented tonight.
There's three changes on this.
I'm going to say template contract for each entity.
One is in the past we had them giving us quarterly financials.
I'm requesting that we change that to happen.
Give us financials when they request a reimbursement.
They, it's just something that they have to come back and cure several times a year.
It becomes a, it's just forgetting.
It's, it's hard to remember.
And the other number two is probably the best.
seven or eight years ago, the council asked, they were looking at reducing the funding to these
organizations and they put in a clause that said, we need your report on January and what
you would do if you're if you're funding those reduced by 10 percent. We've not reduced the funding
and I'm asking that we can't report out. It was just we would receive a simple email that said,
we would just reduce services and that's pretty much what the answer was.
Did we receive those reports? We did. We do receive those reports. If when we don't and not on
time, we bring we bring it before you to cure the contract. The third item is a new item that
we're the cities going to look at doing is accepting a civil rights program or policy and we're
asking for these three entities to provide us with their civil rights policy by December 31st.
Two of them have already provided that policy and the other one we'll get with the contract's
approved. So I'm just asking to approve to approve as presented with the changes.
In that last changes is mandated by federal law. We have to adopt the civil rights policy and part of that
is everybody we give money to has to have a similar civil rights policy. So it's passing along
like federal law versus. I got a question because this came up here recently on the Pellavan.
We give those guys $46,000 a year, but we asked them to help us during the event last weekend to
bus people from if needed from the six center to Main Street and it's $500. They want to charge us.
We end up not using it at all but we still got to pay a $500. So that shouldn't have been anything.
Right. I feel like it fits. If you're going to give it a put on by the city that and we need that.
I mean I'm sure we don't want to take advantage of it, but we may have it in one of the work
with this a little bit. Maybe it two minutes maybe a year or something. That would certainly be something that we could
ingest in that contract. I don't disagree with you at all. You think that the amount of money you're paying and the
good tax we can't say. So that's something we can get into the contract before we approve it. That's what you all want. That's what we can do.
That's what I would like. I don't know what they're about. I also would like, but I feel like it's
a little bit before we're being a good partner paying the 46,000. Yes, they're being a good partner and they're
charged 500. That seems a little extreme to me on that side.
That being the case, might I suggest, we vote on each contract separately.
And there's another reason why we should do that.
That's exactly what I was going to suggest because the other two shouldn't suffer because of one.
Anybody else have any more questions on them?
So we're looking for a motion to approve the community crisis service.
Comrade.
So moved.
I'll say it.
East End Parker?
Aye.
Mr. Stan.
Assembly.
Mr. Stano.
And then.
And we're on table in a good way.
Vote that.
And then we'll be looking for approval on.
Promotion to approve on the Mama Seenier Center.
Assessment.
Saundry.
No second.
Davis.
Parker.
Nice.
East End Park.
The formal, the member.
Aye.
And 12.
Economic Development, Contract.
I think I've developed a services, Mr. Charlotte Allen.
Let's see her here.
So we're going to table that one.
Or.
Which one goes outside?
Charlotte Allen.
I'll see you.
Yes.
Okay. So we'll see.
She's still working on the contract.
Okay. So we'll table them.
12.
13.
Except for reject bid.
See 21 dash 15, the amount of 68,390 dollars to Collins construction company for demolition of the following properties.
One or two ice out east.
One, eleven iron northeast.
One, eighteen, eight north west.
Two, ten, eight north east.
Six, oh, four, ell north west.
And two, eight north west.
Approve contract contingent upon this emission.
A required contract documents.
A approved by city manager or his days.
And it doesn't need to sign.
Notice to proceed.
Let's proceed to the point.
So this is because the contract on this is over.
We've been here that we've come back over 50,000.
And it has to come before the ice.
We did.
A approved.
We did go out to bid.
We had one.
Responded.
As I said.
In the.
We ate.
And that was.
Collins.
Part of the reason.
Price is so high.
On this contract.
It's three of his properties.
And the specialist.
That has to be protected out.
And have it removed.
When he does that.
You guys have someone checking up on him.
Checking up to make sure that it's in the close container.
Taking to an approved landfill.
So another landfill.
And Kansas will take certain kinds of a spest is.
For the same.
The rest of the house.
So he doesn't have this just in the way of certification, what he conquers that out.
So he does have a different company coming in there.
So do we have a grant for this?
No, this is not part of his grant.
This is a city demo that's coming out of the demo of.
So we're making sure that the expenses are removed before he proceeds with the demo.
We don't do an inspection or so.
We contract with Collins and he's responsible for that.
So how do we know he's doing the right thing?
We don't.
No, we don't.
We don't expect to do that.
We don't.
We don't expect it.
We.
We're not certified to inspect that and trust.
You know, as the contractor.
He goes after.
He gets his.
A specialist contract.
To remove it.
And hasn't.
We're going to take care of.
Do we even know if the.
The.
Asbestos contractor even shows up in Miami.
That was.
Yeah.
The house up there.
A close to where they.
This is.
We'll stay on this used to be.
To.
I can't reference to 27 to 29 to 10 to the home.
The contract and 10 with the whole house.
And then.
We.
We work.
So yes, he.
He was.
I mean, that was on the last.
Our queue.
So that's an example.
Yes.
He was on the side.
How did you know.
What.
Well, I'm in there.
I saw it.
Are you going to go to everyone and make sure.
I don't.
I think it's something that.
It should.
I had to happen.
I know when we demoed my church.
Um.
As a big looks.
Asbestos.
And all this stuff is in close containers.
And.
Tended off.
Yes.
That was.
There's a lot of this information.
I'm going to check on one of the three in the process.
As I said they're pretty close.
So I put an.
That's all three just make sure.
It's being done.
Okay, but understand we're not experts.
I mean, nobody make sure he's there.
He's there.
You just are willing.
To verify that.
And the.
I've.
A best to.
But I guess.
If.
This.
how it's supposed to do them up for me.
Right.
And that's in food and in the food.
And included in the contract, that's right.
But does the company that he contract,
providing him with a certificate of what is it?
They're certificate that they have.
saying that they can be an abatement company. We had to do this, so I had the company send
me their certification that they are certified to remove asbestos.
So you will go buy and check on them and make sure they're actually there and do it.
Yes.
And we do have the money that's already budgeted. Correct.
All my commotion.
Second.
Thank you.
Fourteen summer programs at the library, Judy, Cali, and Marsha.
We can jump on the mission at the library as well as all of the department of library
arts and cultures to enhance the quality of our community.
And there's lots of different ways that we do this but we're just going to try a little bit
about what we've done over the summer.
And I have with me, Judy, baby, and our children's library, Song of Haskins, our T-Liberian,
and Cali Fortner, the Assistant Library Director, who's going to talk about the health
literacy.
So we'll start with you.
Okay.
Thank you.
Well, our Center Programming went into a very different looking program as a 2020.
We were used to having lots and lots of people flooding into the library and lots of kids
with three different age group programs going on and when Cali did, we had to kind of rebuild
ourselves.
And so this is a little bit of a summer change, although we haven't had what in-house.
We have had a life of friends in the park and we've been going to, boys and girls club.
We're very partners with them.
So we had two live programs in Riverview Park and we started off at some of our programs
with Tommy Truffet, the Incident of the Kevin Way.
Some of our sponsors, the summer that help us with not only programming the prizes and everything,
the Institute of Museum of Library Services, O-D-L of Women's Heart of Libraries, Feeds of
Heds Freight.
They were helped with prizes, poop, our friends of library paid for these two programs that were
free to the public.
Also, community partners that we work with throughout the year, boys and girls club.
You'll see some slides going right to the farmers market, head start, and the child advocacy
center of the lot of the camp.
project that Sony came up with, and we took it to the farmers market when you need.
We had kids doing art. They got the news here that they're littering, we make sure that
they littered that the farmers market and not the library. That also got a rest of the
car for our boost buttons. And so that was fun. Sony and I were out there enjoying the heat,
just like everybody else. And I mentioned the Boys and Girls Club. I went to both campuses
for about six weeks, did about 15 different programs. I mean, we come up with all our own
programming. This particular slide here is that the new teens in our group have wheel rotters.
And these are, they don't really look like teens. They started at about 11, they call it the
teen center, but they started about age 11. So we were reading this novel out loud that summer.
It takes place in Australia, and there's lots of different really different animals in this book.
And so each week, we would talk about a different animal. We'll do an art project. This is their
Archie Weaver community. Now, this is at the lower grade over in Riverview Park. This is also Boys and Girls
Club, Storytime. Again, always an art project that would have been playing lots of fun. Kids really enjoy it.
Lots of hubs, even though, you know, there's this for like this, but you still get some hubs.
Also, this started last year when we really couldn't have a lot of in-house programming.
So I'm going to start making up bags to give away that had reading materials,
to her kinds of literacy, will activities, and stuff, and always an art project. So I brought one,
just to show you, because for me to say, I gave away 145 brevendows, you really wouldn't know what a
grab a bill is. But it has several materials in it, and always an art project. And here's our old mass
thought, and a man that'll be happy to see is that is, really, see six teachers on here. And so this is something
that was just posted on our Facebook page, but that was the next grab and go. We gave away 145 of those
the summer kids that came in. Here we go. Oh, oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, oh,
I'm sorry. Respect the clicker. Yes, that was okay, there you go. Okay, you're on it. I'm sorry,
I didn't announce to you, but you went on the list, but- Oh, I'm not. I just saw it, yes.
So, having a team librarian is kind of a newer thing, so this was kind of coming from nothing to something.
So, some of our partners that we partnered with, was voicing real stuff.
coming, darkened company, day and on boards, and more. So they've helped most of them
help with our summer vash that will help somewhere about. The boys and girls club
are set with duty, and they came to the library instead of me coming to them. So they got
taking out in our newly improved teens center. So each week we did a weekly draft, they got
to hang out in the teens center, look at books, play games, see what we have there, and then
they're last week with Dean, they did some volunteer work in our base, letting them in our base.
We did some more pictures of them. We did an event at the rocket park that was
for everybody, and that was just being produced. So if you haven't been to the library, we do
have a turtle at the library, so I can come in and see her. So we took her to the park, and we
encouraged patrons to bring some of their unique pets to the park, and we gave some stuff away,
which was nice to have to do with the rocket park, all fixed up when we worked at that.
We do a lot of things online, especially with this COVID time, so we did an excuse at contest.
We had 66 entries, so here's some of the pets that were on there, and one of our winners.
And then summer vash that was our big huge thing, we had on the 27th, we did a cookout, we
had a set of games out for families to come play, and we did a giveaway, we had 75 people.
I'm also a big grab goes, just like we just did, this is the finished product of one of them, and I gave away 70 of those.
I'm Cali, I'm the Assistant Library Director. I applied for and received a $9,000 grant from the Oklahoma Department of
Libraries and the Institute of Museum of Library Services, so that we could do some health literacy
programming that would be free to the community. Some of the things that we did with that are
biggest input that we had from people, our biggest turnout was forced to be summer, since we couldn't
bring people into the library due to COVID to do like hooking demonstrations or things like that.
We chose to do recorded videos online of different movies and we did it four weeks in a row.
We had over 1200 views, so over 1200 people clicked on those videos and watched them and had
me going through making this movie, I put in facts and information about the ingredients and how
they can help your body. We handed out 20 each week and we ran out so fast that the last week
actually did 40. And so we ended up getting out over 100 smoothie kits and we partnered with the
Farmer's Market so that we could hand them out and then you can see me and then our
literacy coordinator, Charlotte there, handing those out and we also went over if they didn't
get to see the video online, the best.
had the recipe in there along with the ingredients so that they could make the
smoothie the only thing we did include was like the milk because it was hot and
we're not gonna try to add out milk but it's under degrees and then we had
I included some quotes there people really really enjoyed it I mean a lot of
people said oh we love it so much we want coffee ingredients and maybe more some
reason blueberries were the biggest hit I don't know what the deal was with blueberries
but almost every survey from that week was like blueberries again and people really
want to see that again next year so we're gonna try to shoot for that for the next
farmers market season again with COVID just like Judy and Sonic we have a
kind of modify what we could do so we reached out to a martial arts academy who
was already doing online classes for COVID and they put on a series some
series of videos each one of six videos long tricking was more for kids I don't know
it's kind of dance martial arts there's a picture of kids doing it at home on
their laptop so they didn't have to come in anywhere at internet access in
Facebook they couldn't do it anywhere and then we did adult fitness that had over
485 views yoga was probably the biggest one the 730 views and then our children's
fitness was 510 views and those are also available on our website and on our
Facebook page so anybody can access them any time it's completely free and then
if anybody follows our Facebook page probably South Json and I then had to do it
online due to the right the Skype and COVID cases recently we also had it in the
newspaper about our cooking classes so we did a pressure cooker class that had
375 views after just two weeks and then our air fryer class had a hundred and
70 views after just a week and half of being up there with our funds we also
a big chunk of that $9,000 went to putting the story walk in it is that rotary
park have been finished but out there I want to say thank you to the Parks Department
because they put all those in for us and if they wouldn't have helped it would have
not happened so a huge thank you to those guys right now our story we had out there
is turtle walk we've taken our turtle out there and actually walked around we
can change those stories out they don't have to just eat children stories we could put
local history information in there we can work for schools and display
projects for our classes of really no limit except our imagination and what we could
do with that so if anybody ever has any ideas of ways we could include other people
within the community and we can do that for that story walk we also did a walking
club in type two classes as well and he was kind enough to allow us to use their
indoor track because of the heat and also we did pick it up again and the winter
time we'll be able to use that so that we can continue to walk without the weather
causing any conflicts and that's the end
So thank you guys so much for giving us time to talk about what we've been doing in the library.
Thank you.
I have some really creative staff and I'm really proud of them.
They've kind of been a lot more cool things to some of.
And when you think about COVID and how that changed,
how lovers had a new things, they were right on it.
But we might be able to use a new ways that we could reach the public.
Thank you.
Is that still a mark packet?
Pardon me.
That's a mark packet.
Yeah.
It's an activities and it's got a little project in your and a story.
What?
I think you should give it a dock on these stuff to put together when we come back.
No.
Hey.
Thank you ladies.
Wow.
15 out of new business that's a business that's supposed to be this agenda.
16 staff reports.
And 17 mayor and council committee and announcements.
I would like to thank Amanda
for a great weekend.
She did a fantastic job.
I've been on the board that she's on.
She makes everybody's job look really easy.
And I really appreciate it and what you've done.
And I'm just tickled the death that your husband loaned you to this.
Thank you for all you do.
I would also like to just throw out that this was the first time we did this.
And I don't think there was any hiccups.
I mean, we had a couple of small things, like especially with my group.
But that was because runners are a weird people.
But man, fantastic.
Not to that apart.
A lot of leaders, including the tribal chief at the Peoria tribe, said he was in awe at how many people were there and how well the events he'd organized.
So that's off to you.
I hate that she walked out of here because I wanted to say two things this afternoon.
I have not always agreed or appreciate it.
Christy, but last Thursday, she did an excellent job with a mixed audience of landlords mostly.
And handled that very, very well.
And I wanted to commend her on that.
And then secondly, I woke up at 218 this morning and it's just one of the things that I do any more of the older I get.
But I was thinking that 35 and a half years ago, Bob Bless and I were in the second semester of our sophomore years.
When, oh, when my I got gut punched.
and good-rich left here, and the events of the last weekend, because of in large part
bow and bless is willingness to take a risk, and aim a little high, and then the execution
of Amanda and team, and all the rest of the city staff that jumped into support her, provided
a sense of pride, maybe we hadn't seen in a really, really long time.
We had been status quo for decades, as far as I was concerned, having been a lifelong resident
other than college, and they were certainly nothing status quo about this weekend.
It was a great event, but forward, anything else we had coming down the fight.
I'd like to cabbage onto what you said about Christy too, because you didn't mention
it, but at the end, one of the landlords that was very, very skeptical, said he felt much better
at the end of this presentation, so I felt that was what we're seeing about Christy.
Christy did handle it very well.
That was an outstanding meeting, and she put it together really well.
I'd add to that, just as we are learning about each other on this council, we're all kind of new
to this, but we engage really, really intensely sometimes, and sometimes it's tough, and sometimes
it's easy, and sometimes we come up with some cool stuff.
I would ask the department, has managers in particular, to let your, you all know for sure
and let your managers and other folks on your staff's know for sure, that we want to know
when they're being exceptional.
Status quo sucks.
It'll always suck.
It'll never be good enough.
We don't want our kids being status quo or mediocre.
We rose above status quo this weekend in the last few days, and that's all I want to do.
And also, high tire, you and Robert, you guys outstanding, I mean, you is there to support
Amanda, and everything she needed, you guys did a fantastic job on yourself, and I definitely
appreciate what you both did also.
But he died.
Right.
It was awesome.
You didn't mean that before I go.
No?
He was like, okay, he should.
He's not a kid.
He's on a kid.
He's a kid.
It looked like a great time.
So, this event this weekend was unbelievable.
And there was something that was in my head that I wanted to do really, really bad, and, you
know, bogg on board, we discussed it.
But.
When we gave it to Amanda Davis, it was over.
This girl flips the switch and she doesn't stop till the job is done.
And she does it to the best of her ability, which is pretty amazing.
I had, we had people from all over.
We had a stage guy that does concerts all over the country.
And he said this one was put together better than any of them he'd done.
That's pretty impressive.
The acts that we had in from Nashville.
So they were treated better here by Amanda and her staff.
They had been treated anywhere.
Those things make people want to come to Miami.
She is probably the biggest cheerleader for this town.
Next to me.
No, but I'm telling you, she goes out.
She works to tell off.
And this week we were together quite a bit.
See each other a lot, talking on the phone a lot.
Because coming down at the end, there was a whole lot of details that got to be worked out.
And she was up late.
I know she got a very little sleep this week.
Her anniversary was this week.
And she didn't get to go out with her husband for anniversary.
So we thank Chad.
I think he's here.
Are you here, Chad?
There you go.
Come on.
Come on, Chad.
So we appreciate Chad and her family for allowing her.
The time to do this for our community.
Because what she did this weekend was she drove a golden spike in the middle of Route 66 with
Myem was name on it.
And she put us on the map.
Because this event that was executed this week for a town of our size was awesome.
And she led it.
And if she hadn't led it, it wouldn't have went off like it did.
This girl is a rock star.
And we cannot let her go anywhere.
Because what she does for this community.
So what that being said, the mayor and the city council along with your city manager and
your city attorney would like to give you an anniversary card.
So when you and Chad come up and get this.
And we thank you both.
And we want you.
I know you guys are heading out Thursday.
And we want to give you that to have a good time.
Thank you.
I love you guys.
I think that's it for us.
Now you go.
I know.
I'm crying.
Well, excellent job.
Very well deserved.
I'll tell you, I couldn't be any more proud of getting to watch this whole team come together and execute this.
Everybody at the city stepping up.
Jumping in to do what had to be done.
The coordination that it took was phenomenal.
The coordination of the community.
I mean, you know, we talk about.
be security or fire safety. We had folks from tribes and county and everybody pulled together
to do what had to be done. Our partners at GRDA providing resources, tribal resources,
county resources. We had 30, 7 on security folks on here that didn't give a time. They're
very event, which made a huge difference. The presence of our first responders there and available
was awesome. Obviously we didn't have any major events that I'm aware of, so if we did,
you'll have to tell me everything. Everything went off smoothly there, but the town looks amazing.
I don't know about you all, but just drive around and look at our streets and our sidewalks and
curves and other signs and the flower beds around the signs and everything looks a maximum. Kevin and
his team and the parks and streets and it's the sanitation. Oh my gosh, these guys were out
cleaning up. I mean when this thing was wrapping up at 12, one o'clock in the morning, they're out
there, sweeping streets and picking up trash and empty in 72 trash bins up and down Main Street.
So that the next morning, everything looked to make it. And Sunday morning, I had got out
actually as closer around noon and I got out and drove down Main Street because I wanted to see what I was
in for. What it looked like and you could tell anybody was there. Other than the barriers that were in the street,
there was no trash, no nothing, no dumpster, no barrels, nothing. And again, it was just the pride
everybody took in this was phenomenal and how well it went off and the cool thing is, it's now after
our bid, it makes me doubt that everything looks so beautiful. Robert, thank you. You did awesome. You did.
Brother, I kept seeing you and then just running every time I turned a corner, you were there,
zippin' and doing something. Thank you. Somebody says, can you do that to Canada?
Do you want the capability? Well, I'm saying the productivity he got out of this thing was pretty cool.
Well, I'm just standing in line because we're high tired and Robert wants one thing. That guy's one
and then, of course, Amanda staff, God love him. She was barking orders at him.
No, it stopped for days and they were just running. Hoping to get everything done and it was cool to
watch it all come together and come off. What appeared to be so flawless? 140 people. Wow.
Working with the event. It's pretty phenomenal, but you know, the cool thing is, we learned a lot.
We're going to be tracking our numbers and making sure we understand the full extent of what it costs us
and we're going to watch the full extent of the revenue that all of our businesses and like.
We're able to track our hotel, I mean our hotels, we're full and we're flowing and we have
large groups calling us saying they had to go to the job one because everything was filled
up and that is just really cool.
The next year is going to be bigger and we are ready for next year.
Take our lessons learned and vendors are already calling and I hear the number.
Do you see three agencies calling day about building the ads?
Three agencies calling that book and acts we've also got vendors that were calling asking
about the revenue.
It sounded like these were new vendors that had been here before but we're here during the
event and now they want to participate in our radio.
And we had sponsors, our people call and say they want to sponsor next year, they
had to sponsor this year.
They're already looking forward to sponsor next year.
So, do you have anything you want to say?
You said before but I see that a lot of a lot of them have well been ever been when we were
forward and the purpose of this to mean better.
The cool thing was we have a lot of institutional knowledge.
HT, you wouldn't know it but his institutional knowledge and pulling off a research
he was pretty neat and he was able to bring that to the table and help us which was really
neat, Brian and his experience working out in the Fioria buffalo run and knowing how
that went.
It was really exciting.
It's really cool.
Can't wait to do it again and knock the socks off over.
I'm not trying to take credit for anything but I've preached working together since I've
taken over his mayor and this weekend shows what we can do as a community if we work together.
We can pull off anything.
I mean we had people saying this would never work.
This would be a disaster and I don't see those people in the room today because it was very
successful.
And the estimates I've heard on numbers, you know, we went from 20,000 to 30,000 if we don't know
if we're really going to get a matter of number.
That's huge for our community.
That's 30,000.
30?
Awesome.
So, you know, there were no traffic issues.
Now, we did work ahead and talking about, you know, people pulling together.
I would not was working with this, OTA.
Turn back authority was working with us and the highway control.
We all met.
I'd tell her and I went down to the met with him ahead of time and they were going to be monitoring
all the toll booths.
And in traffic, they brought in signs, digital signage.
Of course, no cost of the city.
They just brought in the digital signage and put it in our town to direct people as they're
believing where they wanted to exit out of town.
But obviously it all worked.
great because again I never saw any traffic and I don't know where these people came from
or how they got in here.
Where they parked because parking was never to be there.
But what did we did?
We did it right.
So we can repeat that again.
But again, you know, the pulling together and everybody working.
Pulling on the rope in the same direction.
Maybe you should.
And H.T.
Put on the, he did a handle to car show, the Marseille show, Pokeron.
And when I walk around talking to people, they were saying,
this is a fabulous car show.
But for your first one, you guys knocked out of the park.
We're coming back.
We had, how many entries do we have?
101.
So I mean, everything really went smooth.
We were, we were waiting for the something to go wrong and it just didn't.
Everything ran smooth.
Even the pickle ball tournament.
The sheriff ran that.
Hold no.
We had to put it in the fire department.
The fire department, the fire department did run the corner.
So we had 140 runners that are run there.
And how's that there in the normal?
No, but it was expected because this was, we didn't do it last year.
It was more than we expected this year.
I was put it like that.
That's why.
It was hot.
So next year, I think we're going to do it in our earlier.
Why?
I don't know.
I don't think he left it to a clock in the morning like you do.
Did he?
I don't know.
And it certainly a big thank you to our tribes that pitched in.
That were there working.
Working alongside of us.
Chief Cook.
Bless her souls.
Running VIPs on a golf cart.
Back and forth, back and forth.
Cross, cross, mainstream.
All day.
In a hundred degree heat.
I rode with her.
And I suggested riding with her early in the day.
That lady's a workhorse.
She is.
And she can probably work me under the table.
I want to get both of you to do because his leadership really led us to this thing.
He's that steady solid guy.
Now, I did see him when we were in a man's office on Thursday.
The day before they went, I asked her.
I said give me a number.
I know you can't be spot on but give me a ballpark.
And she says for both days.
I said yes for both days.
She said 30,000.
And both said, oh my gosh, I want to be you.
But it worked.
Well, we got a great team.
There's a lot to be put.
This community has a lot to be proud of.
It was very emotional for me.
Having been gone for 30 years.
And one of the things that I had talked with the council about when I came back.
I can't help but always have those memories.
back when I was a kid, the sidewalks out. That was just something that was really special.
To me, to look forward to every summer, and me and my friends making plans to get up, get
on our bikes, and boy, we're going to be down here on our bikes, you know, six AM, and walking
up and down, mainstream this weekend. It was emotional. It was awesome.
We worried about the award for the best shoppers, but yeah, she didn't get it.
I would like to full advantage of her. She did a great job. Well, we got 363 days. We'll get
do it all over you.
And then we're doing a set of that tomorrow, but our committee will all be in the next Friday and 13th.
I think that's very good. And then we'll move on to the ballroom, and we will
go and watch that with a good start to finish. We'll go through gives them ads, and then once we get a
game plan, and as much as we don't like to do it, the pot is going in, and because their layout
really gets a big fact. I mean, we'll get the good bat and I believe that I think that's fine. We didn't have
some businesses. If you guys do get calls of this one, something that weren't happy that we have
the road shut down all day on Friday, but with our contracts and been going to test it this,
they have 20 and 20 on Facebook, and these national acts. And the contract with the stage committee in
the security, and having that secure location was a big deal. We kind of didn't have a choice. I mean,
we had to have everything secured. And there was a lot going on Friday, and that's where it's playing.
And we hope that that didn't show them to you guys, that they have set up the people they've
seen in the press doors, that they can access it from the back, so we're kind of still trying to work out some
of that stuff, but the thought is to really try to let the community have voice, and have some deep
back to messing with it. There's things that we can do to make it better, we'll look at them. We
like a lot, we were. We're going to do a lot of things wrong, and we'll fix that. I know I won't.
Do you want to say something?
I would like to recognize the takers, because they were big ones. Yes, they were big stations and
Valerie and dispatch were in there. Yes, go absolutely. This one is the band, so. They did amazing.
Truly, a bunch of great parties. Tyler's electric crew, they did amazing job running electric
geldies while these boosts. Well, to be clear, they were wiring on the fly at that point.
Rewire the main street to accommodate all that we did.
It was a good job. I'm going to take an army to get this done and just
think we had a great album to lead us on.
I'm in your time, sorry.
You're, I said there's a couple of things I want to mention real quick.
This is the last week that the pool will be open full for a full week.
It'll be 1 to 6 this week and then 1 to 6 on the weekends of August 14 to 15 and then
21st and 22nd and 22nd will be the last day that it's opened.
And our day of the tenets has been really good at around 175.
That's a good average that we've had.
But, you know, considering what we had to do to get there and get it open,
but we did it, glad we got there and I think our citizens appreciate what was done.
Splash Pad is still running full steam ahead and it will remain open through minutes
September as long as kids are willing to go out and get them in the water.
Bless their little hearts.
So, as long as it's warm enough, it'll keep running.
Last thing I wanted to mention and I'll probably have Jill help me if I screw this up.
We do need to mention the issue we had with the bill, ironically.
So, we had made some changes recently to our billing.
This is actually something that I think Josh had actually started some of the
conversations around the modifications to the bill.
And the modifications, one at a couple of the modifications, obviously,
adding some graphs that had been put on there.
But in order to do this, we had made changes in the way that we produced the bills and print the bills.
And we have noticed that in the billing cycle that we just ran.
The very first one with these modifications.
There's a pair.
Now, it's not the end of the world, it's not horrible, but it's not great.
So, we'll have to do some communication.
But essentially, on the bill, when it was printed, the amount to everything is correct.
But as most bills have, there is an amount to do after.
And it's a generally a number that's on the bottom that after the due date.
There's what it's a 10% bill, a late fee that's applied.
And so it just normally calculates the late fee to the amount due.
And in this case, it printed zeros.
So, the way the bill reads today is that if your bill is late, it's zero amount due.
So, we'll have to hope that everybody understands that the amount due is the actual amount due.
And that zero is not correct.
And there's just a year.
Josh, opposed on the shit show would be appropriate about that.
Yeah.
We're blaming it on you because you made us change it.
Well, Josh's doing a very good changes.
Yeah, one key.
At least the amount is right.
I have to get it.
All right.
That's all I'm going to do, Jim.
So move. Second.
Davis.
Five.